<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Desire to Inquire</title>
    <description>A blog about one man&#39;s quest to become a self-directed learner</description>
    <link>http://desiretoinquire.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://desiretoinquire.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Concerning the Quest</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One month ago, I made the rather big decision (at least for me) to quit my masters program and embark on a new but life-long quest to become a wholy self-educated person. Though this blog, I plan to document what I’m learning about self-directed-learning. I look forward to sharing and swapping insights with you and hope to become resource to those who are are on this journey with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the posts I plan to publish in the coming weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More details of why I quit my masters (aka my philosophy of learning)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The meaning of “desire to inquire” and the importance of inquiring to learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The inspirational people in my life–my mentors, teachers, and examples &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a web designer and the architect of this site design, I also plan to enhance the look and functionality of this site over time. Some things to come:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some really cool, meaningful logo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An “About” page with background info &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More images and possibly some texture to add character&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to comment on posts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Categories for organization once I have a more than a few posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining me! Stay turned for weekly posts and please &lt;a href=&quot;http://desiretoinquire.com/feed.xml&quot;&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; (if that’s your thing).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://desiretoinquire.com//2014/10/01/concerning-the-quest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://desiretoinquire.com//2014/10/01/concerning-the-quest.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
